# **Nishant Dougall (they / them)**

M: 0412 202 666 | E: nishantdougall@gmail.com

### **Summary**

I have a diploma in community services, a bachelor's degree in business, and a master's degree in finance. I have four years in community services which includes two years as a community support worker providing emergency relief to residents of Banyule and Nillimbik, and a background in project management and eight years of experience in financial services

I am queer, neuro-diverse, gender diverse, and a person of colour. I have lived experience of psychosocial disability, discrimination, homelessness, financial hardship, shame, and inequality and social injustice. I am trauma-informed and excel in roles requiring strong interpersonal skills, empathy and imaginative problem-solving.

I've moved away from the corporate world to pursue my passion for social justice and contribute to organisations driving bold and imaginative change.

#### **Key Skills**

- Strong communication and interpersonal skills, with a proven ability to interact compassionately and respectfully with people in crisis who are experiencing financial and food insecurity.
- Possess local knowledge of the community services sector in Naarm.
- Assessing complex needs and providing interventions and referrals.
- Creating safe environments for children and young people.
- Proficient in record-keeping and navigation of databases such as CISVic.
- Flexibility, adaptability, and a guick learner.
- Proven ability to provide inclusive, non-discriminatory, person-led, strengths-based support to people of every ethnicity, faith, age, disability, culture, language, gender identity, sex, and sexual orientation.

#### **Qualifications and Certifications**

- Diploma of Community Services | Melbourne Polytechnic | 2024
- Master of Finance | Monash University | 2008
- Bachelor of Business (Marketing) | Queensland Uni of Technology | 2005
- Working With Children Check | Victorian State Government | 2023
- First Aid | St John Ambulance Australia | 2023
- Mental Health First Aid | Mental Health First Aid Australia | 2021

### **Work Experience**

### headspace | Internship - Refugee and Migrant Practice Team | Apr 2024 - current

 Collaborated with 20 international students to conduct focus groups and gather qualitative data on client needs. • Coded participant responses and conducted a thematic analysis, contributing to a 50-page research findings report to inform culturally sensitive program design.

### Diamond Valley Community Support | Community Support Worker | Nov 2022-2024

- Assessed 400+ clients with complex needs to identify needs and goals, and referred them to appropriate support services.
- Built strong relationships with diverse clients with complex needs and provided trauma-informed care.
- Supported vulnerable clients with complex needs by providing crisis intervention, advocacy, and access to essential resources, including housing, financial assistance, and mental health support.

### Thorne Harbour Health | Aug 2018 - Dec 2021

- COVID19 Food Delivery Volunteer (Jun 2020 Dec 2021): Supported members of the LGBTIQ+ community during the COVID-19 pandemic by delivering over 1000 food packages to socially isolated and immunocompromised individuals.
- Sex on Premise Venue Outreach Volunteer (Dec 2018 Dec 2019): Provided support to over 100 clients at sex-on-premises venues, answering questions about sexual health, HIV, mental health, and substance use, and suggesting appropriate referrals.
- Re-Wired v2.0 Volunteer Peer Support Facilitator (Aug 2018 Jan 2019): Facilitated a
  peer support group based on harm minimisation SMART Recovery framework, for LGBTIQ+
  individuals seeking to change substance use behaviors, utilizing the SMART

### Royal Bank of Scotland | Senior Business Analyst | Jan 2016 - Dec 2019

• Lead analyst on a regulatory compliance project, successfully establishing effective collaborations with stakeholders and external organizations.

# Independent TV News | Business Analyst | Jan 2014 - Dec 2015

- Lead analyst on a tech project in ITN's Finance dept, responsible for creating and managing staff training & project communications.
- Supported the project manager in implementing a new accounting software package.

### National Australia Bank | Project Analyst | Dec 2010 - Dec 2013

- Identified and documented requirements for a new centralized process on a significant transformational change program.
- Designed the solution, drafted appropriate documents, and maintained records per NAB's policies and procedures regarding project delivery.

## National Australia Bank | Graduate Program | Jan 2009 - Nov 2010

Supported manager in managing a portfolio of 100 small business clients in Carlton